<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--	ident	"@(#)GUIDE.xml	1.14	04/06/30 GED" -->
<html>
<head>
<title>AFE and MXFE Ethernet Drivers</title>
<author>Garrett D'Amore</author>
<docnumber>Version <version/></docnumber>
<copyright>Copyright 2002-2004</copyright>
</head>
<body>
<chaphead>About This Book</chaphead>
<p>
This book describes installing, configuring, and troubleshooting the
<tt>afe</tt> and <tt>mxfe</tt> ethernet drivers for Solaris<sup>TM</sup>
platforms.
</p>
<p>
These ethernet drivers support a number of low-cost PCI-based
fast ethernet controllers, which are used in quite a variety of
network cards and on-board network interfaces. 
Specifically, these drivers support devices based on the ADMtek Centaur
and Comet controllers, the Macronix 98715 family, and the Lite-On PNIC-II
controllers.
</p>
<section>Intended Audience</section>
<p>
This book is intended for system administrators administering ethernet
devices.  You should be familiar with basic Solaris system administration.
If you do not have these skills, you may wish to ask a more experienced
system administrator for assistance.  There are also numerous classes
offered throughout the world that can help with this.
</p>

<p>
In order to perform the tasks outlined in this document, you must have
<tt>root</tt> privileges for your system.
</p>

<section>Typographic Conventions</section>
<p>
The following table lists the typographic conventions used in this manual.
</p>
<p>
<table bogus cellpadding="5" width="100%" border="1">
<tr>
<th>Typeface</th>
<th>Meaning</th>
<th>Example</th>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><tt>AaBbCc123</tt></td>
<td>On-screen output, commands, files and directories.</td>
<td>Use <tt>showrev -p</tt> to list the patches on your system.</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><entry>AaBbCc123</entry></td>
<td>User input as typed exactly in on-screen output and examples.</td>
<td><tt>csh% </tt><entry>pkginfo</entry></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><var>AaBbCc12</var></td>
<td>Variable text, used in examples for text that should be replaced with a real value.</td>
<td><tt>csh% </tt><entry>cd</entry> <var>directory</var></td>
</tr>
</table>
</p>
<p>
</p>
<section>Feedback</section>
<p>
I welcome feedback regarding this document, and the software which
it documents, in the hope that the end product will be improved.
Please send your comments to me at 
&lt;<a href="mailto:garrett@damore.org">garrett@damore.org</a>&gt;.
</p>

<section>Copyright</section>
<p>
Copyright &copy; 2002, 2003 Garrett D'Amore,
&lt;<a href="mailto:garrett@damore.org">garrett@damore.org</a>&gt;.
</p>
<p>
All rights reserved.  Redistribution and use in source, binary, and
printed forms, with or without modification, are permitted  provided
that the following conditions are met:
</p>
<ol>
<li>Redistributions in any form must retain the above copyright
notice, this list of conditions and the following disclaimer.</li>
<li>Neither the name of the author nor the names of any co-contributors
may be used to endorse or promote products derived from this software
without specific prior written permission.</li>
</ol>
<section>Disclaimer</section>
<p>
THIS DOCUMENT IS PROVIDED "AS IS" WITHOUT WARRANTY OF ANY KIND, EITHER
EXPRESS OR IMPLIED, INCLUDING, BUT NOT LIMITED TO, THE IMPLIED WARRANTIES
OF MERCHANTABILITY, FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE, OR NON-INFRINGEMENT.
</p>
<section>Trademarks</section>
<p>
Sun, Sun Microsystems, and Solaris<sup>TM</sup> are
trademarks, registered trademarks, or service marks of Sun Microsystems, Inc. 
SPARC<sup>&reg;</sup> and UltraSPARC<sup>&reg;</sup> are
registered trademarks of SPARC International, Inc.  Intel<sup>&reg;</sup> is a
registered trademark of Intel Corporation.  Other marks are the property
of their respective owners.
</p>

<chaphead>Chapter 1 - Before You Begin</chaphead>

<section>System Requirements</section>
<p>
This software requires Solaris 7 or newer on Intel processors, or Solaris 8 or
newer running on SPARC processors. In order to use IPv6, you will need to use
Solaris 8 or newer.
</p>

<note>
Solaris 8 users on SPARC will require patch 109202-01
or newer.  This patch is available from
<a href="http://sunsolve.sun.com/">http://sunsolve.sun.com/</a>.  This patch
is included with Solaris 8 10/00 and newer.
</note>

<p>
You must also have a device which is supported by these drivers,
which can be either a PCI card, CardBus card, or an on-board device.  The most
up-to-date list of supported devices can be found on-line at <a
href="http://garrett.damore.org/software/ethernet/support.shtml">http://garrett.damore.org/software/ethernet/support.shtml</a>
</p>

<p>
If the device is not built in to your system, you will need an
available compatible slot for the card.  Typically this means a
bus-mastering capable PCI slot, with
support for 32-bit, 33 MHz devices.  On modern systems, almost any
PCI slot will meet this requirement.  (At the time of this writing, the
author is unaware of any SPARC system with PCI slots that do not meet
this requirement.)
</p>

<p>
CardBus slots are available on systems from some vendors, and support
CardBus devices which are compatible with these drivers.
Note also that the slot must support the full 32-bit CardBus
standard -- many systems have only support for 16-bit PC cards, and hence
cannot support CardBus devices.  Check with your system vendor for more
information.
</p>

<warning>
These drivers do not support removal of CardBus devices
while they are in use; removing a CardBus device while it is in use will
probably crash your system.
</warning>

<p>
See the manuals that came with your system for
information about the slots in your particular system.
</p>

<p>
You will also need an ethernet network to which to connect.  This can
be in the form of a hub, switch, bridge, or direct connection to
another computer using an ethernet cross-over cable.  If you need
help, you should contact your network administrator.
</p>

<p>
Additionally, you will need to know the configuration parameters
for your network (IP address, hostname, netmask, default router, 
and DNS servers if appropriate).  You should contact your network administrator
to obtain these parameters for your system if you do not already know them.
</p>

<p>
You will need to use <tt>root</tt> privileges in order to complete the
tasks in this manual, so you must be in possession of the root password,
or have equivalent access.
<p>

</p>
Finally, you will also need a small amount of disk space on your root
disk in order to complete the installation.  The recommended minimum free
space is 5 megabytes.
</p>

<chaphead>Chapter 2 - Installation</chaphead>

<p>This chapter describes installing the software for the ethernet device
drivers.</p>

<section>Downloading the Software</section>

<p>
In order to install the software, you must first obtain it.  Fortunately,
the device drivers you will need are freely available on the Internet at the URL
<a href="http://garrett.damore.org/software/ethernet/">http://garrett.damore.org/software/ethernet/</a>.
</p>
<p>
There are several different files you can download.  Typically you will
want to pick up one of either the
<tt>etherdrivers-</tt><var>version</var>-<tt>sparc.zip</tt> or
<tt>etherdrivers-</tt><var>version</var>-<tt>i386.zip</tt> files.
 You can also grab
the source code, which is located in a file named
<tt>etherdrivers-</tt><var>version</var><tt>-src.zip</tt>.  In all these cases,
<var>version</var>
refers to the latest version, which at the time of this writing was
<version/>.
</p>

<note>There may be older releases of the software available on the web site 
as well.  Since these probably have bugs that have been fixed in later 
releases, you are encouraged to stick with the latest release.</note>

<section>Uncompressing the Package</section>
<p>
Now that you have got the software, you should <tt>unzip</tt>(1) it in
an appropriate scratch directory.  The following example shows this being
done for version <version/> on SPARC.
</p>
<screen>
csh% <entry>cp etherdrivers-<version/>-sparc.zip /var/tmp</entry>
csh% <entry>cd /var/tmp</entry>
csh% <entry>unzip etherdrivers-<version/>-sparc.zip</entry>
csh% <entry>cd etherdrivers-<version/></entry>
</screen>

<section>Installing the Packages</section>

<p>
Before you can install the software, you must become the superuser
(for example by using the <tt>su</tt>(1M) command.)
</p>

<screen>
csh% <entry>su</entry>
Password: 
#
</screen>

<p>
The next step is to install the software packages.  This is done
by executing the <tt>pkgadd</tt>(1M) command, as shown below:
</p>

<screen>
# <entry>pkgadd -d Packages/</entry><var>arch</var><entry> all</entry>
</screen>

<p>
The <var>arch</var> is assumed to refer to <tt>sparc</tt> or <tt>i386</tt>.
You can determine the correct value by executing the following command: 
</p>

<screen>
csh% <entry>uname -p</entry>
</screen>

<note>You may be asked to answer additional questions,
if <tt>pkgadd</tt> determines that it needs more information.  See
the <tt>pkgadd</tt>(1M) or <tt>admin</tt>(4) manual pages for
information about this.</note>

<section>Checking your Installation</section>

<p>
After software is installed, you should check the installation to make
sure that the system has recognized the device driver, as well as any
associated devices.
</p>

<p>
The simplest way to do this is to run the diagnostic utility to identify
the devices that are present in the system.  Do this by executing the
<tt>etherdiag</tt>(1M) utility, as shown in the following example:
</p>
<screen>
root# <b>/opt/GEDnet/bin/etherdiag</b>
Interface: afe0
Model: Accton EN5251
Speed: 100 Mbps
Duplex: full
Media: twpair
Ethernet Address: 0:0:e8:0:0:8f
</screen>

<p>
At this point the software is installed properly, but the device has
not been configured for use with any network protocols.  The next chapter
will explain how to configure the device so that you can use it.
</p>

<section>Updating Your Shell Settings</section>

<p>
The diagnostic software and manual pages are installed under
<tt>/opt/GEDnet/bin</tt> and <tt>/opt/GEDnet/man</tt>.  You may wish
to modify your shell settings appropriately.  The following example
displays this for <tt>csh</tt>(1) users.
</p>

<screen>
csh% <b>setenv PATH ${PATH}:/opt/GEDnet/bin</b>
csh% <b>setenv MANPATH ${MANPATH}:/opt/GEDnet/man</b>
</screen>

<p>
This will make the commands and manual pages available in your environment
without needing to specify the full path.  For example, the manual page
for the driver can be read using the following command:
</p>

<screen>
csh% <b>man afe</b>
</screen>

<p>
See the manual page for <tt>man</tt>(1) for more information.
</p>

<section>Removing the Software</section>

<p>If you want to remove the software, you must first ensure that the
device is not currently in use.  Typically, you must do this by
removing any interface configuration files you created for the interface
(such as <tt>/etc/hostname.</tt><var>interface</var>).  You may need to
also edit configuration files, for example to modify default routes,
etc.
</p>

<p>For a full discussion of network configuration, or (in this case)
unconfiguration, please refer to the
<cite>Solaris 8 System Administration Guide, Volume 3</cite>.
</p>

<p>
Once you have deconfigured the interface, you can safely remove the
software.  This is easily done by executing the following command:
</p>

<screen>
# <entry>pkgrm GEDenetu GEDenetd GEDenetm</entry>
</screen>

<p>
You will need to answer 'y' to certain prompts in order to proceed.
After this is complete, the software will have been removed from your
system.  You may need to reboot to remove the drivers from memory,
however.
</p>

<chaphead><a name="Chap3">Chapter 3 - Configuring Your Ethernet Device</a></chaphead>

<p>This chapter describes the steps to configure your device for use
in a network.</p>

<section>Configuring for IPv4 with Fixed Address</section>

<p>
To configure for a fixed IPv4 address, you must place the IP
address of your network in <tt>/etc/hostname.</tt><var>interface</var>,
where <var>interface</var> is the name of the interface to use, such
as <tt>afe0</tt>.  The following example shows this, for a system
that wishes to use the IP address 192.168.128.101.  (Replace with your
real IP address.)
</p>

<screen>
# <entry>echo 192.168.128.101 &gt; /etc/hostname.afe0</entry>
</screen>

<p>
The interface will now automatically be configured the next time the system
boots.  To configure the interface for immediate use, without rebooting,
the the <tt>ifconfig</tt>(1M) command can be used.  Note that you must
first "plumb" the interface using a command of the following form:
</p>

<screen>
# <entry>ifconfig </entry><var>interface</var><entry> plumb</entry>
</screen>

<p>
Until the interface is plumbed in this fashion, it will not display in
the list of available interfaces (with the <tt>ifconfig -a</tt> command.)
</p>

<p>
Note that this is only the first part of network configuration.  You may
have to edit several other files, such as <tt>/etc/hosts</tt>,
<tt>/etc/resolv.conf</tt>, <tt>/etc/netmasks</tt>,
and <tt>/etc/defaultrouter</tt> to properly configure your
network.
</p>

<p>
The generalities of network configuration on Solaris are well documented
in the <cite>Solaris 8 System Administration Guide, Volume 3</cite>, which
can be accessed on-line at
<a href="http://docs.sun.com/">http://docs.sun.com/</a>.
</p>

<section>Configuring for IPv4 with DHCP</section>

<p>
To set up your ethernet device to act as a client
for DHCP (Dynamic Host Configuration Protocol) you must create
a file <tt>/etc/dhcp.</tt><var>interface</var>.  This file should
contain the word <tt>primary</tt> if the interface is your primary
(or only) network interface.  This will cause DHCP to be used to
set the hostname, default route, and other global parameters for
the system, in addition to the interface-specific configuration.
</p>
<p>
If the file is empty, then DHCP is only used to configure the interface
and global parameters such as the hostname will not be adjusted.
</p>
<p>
The following example shows how to enable the interface <tt>mxfe0</tt>
as the primary (and only) interface, using DHCP.
</p>

<screen>
# <entry>echo primary &gt; /etc/dhcp.mxfe0</entry>
</screen>

<p>
Note that the configuration does not take effect until the next
time the system is rebooted.  The <tt>auto-dhcp</tt> sub-command
of <tt>ifconfig</tt> can be used to configure the interface from DHCP
without rebooting.  (The interface must first be "plumbed" though.)
The following example demonstrates use of <tt>ifconfig</tt>
to configure <tt>afe1</tt> via DHCP for temporary use without rebooting.
</p>

<screen>
# <entry>ifconfig afe1 plumb auto-dhcp</entry>
</screen>

<p>
See the <tt>ifconfig</tt>(1M) manual page for more information.
</p>

<section>Configuring for IPv6 with Autoconfiguration</section>

<p>
In IPv6, address autoconfiguration is commonly used to configure the
address(es) that are used on a network interface.  In most cases, static
addresses will not be used with IPv6.  To configure the device to use
address autoconfiguration (for example, via the neighbor discovery protocol),
all one needs to do is create an empty
<tt>/etc/hostname6.</tt><var>interface</var> file.  For example, the
following command enables IPv6 to be used with address autoconfiguration
on the <tt>mxfe0</tt> interface.
</p>

<screen>
# <entry>touch /etc/hostname6.mxfe0</entry>
</screen>

<p>
Similar to the IPv4 case, this does not take effect until the machine
is rebooted.
To configure an interface for IPv6 autoconfiguration temporarily, without
rebooting, use a command similar to the following:
</p>

<screen>
# <entry>ifconfig mxfe0 inet6 plumb up</entry>
</screen>

<section>Configuring for IPv6 with Static Addressing</section>

<p>
Static addressing is much less likely to be used with IPv6, but
it can still be done.  With static IP addressing, one just needs to
put the hostname or IPv6 address in the <tt>/etc/hostname6.</tt><var>interface</var> file.
</p>

<p>
Again, a reboot is required for this to take effect.  There is also
an <tt>ifconfig</tt> command that can be used for this as well.  It
typically takes the form:
</p>

<screen>
# <entry>ifconfig afe0 inet6 plumb addif 1234::5678/64 up</entry>
</screen>

<p>
In the above address the address 1234::5678/64 was added to the <tt>afe0</tt>
interface.  Please refer to the <cite>Solaris 8 System Administration Guide, Volume 3</cite> for more information about IPv6 addressing.
</p>

<section>Configuring for Use with Other Protocols</section>

<p>
There are protocols besides IPv4 and IPv6 that can be used with ethernet.
Some examples of these are Apple's AppleTalk and Novell's IPX/SPX protocols.
These protocols should work fine with your new ethernet device.  The details
of configuring such protocols to use the ethernet device should be documented
in your network protocol software documentation.  You should be able to just
replace the name of your interface (for example <tt>afe0</tt>) for the
name of any other "standard" interface (for example <tt>hme0</tt>) to which the
documentation might refer.
</p>
<p>
Note however while all this <em>should</em> work, it has not be tested for
use with these drivers, so your results may vary.  But it is hoped and believed
that these drivers will function properly with any other Solaris networking
software.  The author would like very much to learn about any cases to the
contrary.
</p>

<chaphead>Chapter 4 - Diagnostics and Troubleshooting</chaphead>

<p>This chapter describes diagnostic and troubleshooting procedures
for use with the ethernet device.  Note that to use most of the commands in
this chapter, you must run them as <tt>root</tt>.</p>

<section>Using the <tt>etherdiag</tt>(1M) Command</section>

<p>The <tt>etherdiag</tt>(1M) utility can be used to determine which
devices are in your system along with other information about those
devices, such as the ethernet address, manufacturer, link speed, and assorted
other information.  Normally it should be run without any options,
to get a full listing for your system.  Here is an example on one system:
</p>

<screen>
root# <entry>/opt/GEDnet/bin/etherdiag</entry>
Interface: afe0
Model: Accton EN5251
Speed: 100 Mbps
Duplex: full
Media: twpair
Ethernet Address: 0:0:e8:0:0:8f
</screen>

<p>
If you would like to obtain more information, merely add the verbose
flag (<tt>-v</tt>) which, will cause the utility to display more
information.  If used twice, this flag causes even more output to
be displayed.  When submitting bug or problem reports, it is best to
include the full (<tt>-v -v</tt>) output from this command.
</p>

<p>
See the <tt>etherdiag</tt>(1M) manual page for more options that can
be used.
</p>

<section>Using the <tt>snoop</tt>(1M) Command</section>

<p>
Perhaps one of the most useful diagnostic utilities for network
troubleshooting is the <tt>snoop</tt>(1M) utility which is bundled with
Solaris.  This utility can be used to watch packets traveling across
the ethernet.
</p>

<note>The <tt>snoop</tt> utility will cause your interface to run
at reduced performance, so it isn't a good idea to leave it running
for long periods of time, or whenever performance is critical.</note>

<p>
To run <tt>snoop</tt> on a specific interface, use the <tt>-t</tt>
<var>device</var> option.  The example below shows <tt>snoop</tt> running on <tt>afe0</tt>:
</p>

<screen>
# <entry>snoop -d afe0</entry>
Using device /dev/afe (promiscuous mode)

    doc-afe0 -> 192.168.128.209 UDP D=64292 S=34614 LEN=104
    doc-afe0 -> 192.168.128.209 UDP D=64292 S=34614 LEN=64
192.168.128.209 -> doc-afe0     UDP D=34614 S=64292 LEN=80
    doc-afe0 -> 192.168.128.209 UDP D=64292 S=34614 LEN=876
    doc-afe0 -> 192.168.128.209 UDP D=64292 S=34614 LEN=64

</screen>

<p>
There are numerous other options for <tt>snoop</tt>, which allow
disabling promiscuous mode, capturing packets to a file, and enabling
more verbose display.  Please read the manual page for more information
about this useful utility.
</p>

<section>Using the <tt>netstat</tt>(1M) Command</section>

<p>
The <tt>netstat</tt> command is useful for monitoring various
information regarding the IP stack on your machine.  This utility
is complex, and is not covered fully here, but the <tt>-i</tt> option
can be useful to give an overview of the interfaces on your system.
</p>

<p>
The following example is taken from a system with two network interfaces,
one of which is the stock <tt>eri0</tt> supplied with the system, and one
of which is the <tt>afe0</tt> device which was added in afterwards.  The
<tt>lo0</tt> interface is not a real network interface, but is an internal
software loopback.
</p>

<screen>
# <entry>netstat -i</entry>
Name  Mtu  Net/Dest      Address        Ipkts  Ierrs Opkts  Oerrs Collis Queue
lo0   8232 loopback      localhost      4991935 0     4991935 0     0      0
eri0  1500 doc           doc            2835250 1     3652228 298   0      0
afe0  1500 doc-afe0      doc-afe0       1491228 0     5605143 45    0      0
</screen>

<section>Getting Statistics with <tt>kstat</tt>(1M)</section>

<p>
These device drivers maintain a number of statistics, which can be
useful in determining a number of things about the device.  The
simplest way to view these statistics (on Solaris 8 and later) is
with the <tt>kstat</tt>(1M) command.  Here is an example for <tt>mxfe1</tt>.
Note the colon (:) separating <tt>mxfe</tt> (the driver) from <tt>1</tt> (the
PPA, or device instance.)
</p>

<screen>
# kstat mxfe:1 
module: mxfe                            instance: 1     
name:   mxfe1                           class:    net                           
        align_errors                    0
        blocked                         0
        brdcstrcv                       87
        brdcstxmt                       1911
        carrier_errors                  45
        collisions                      0
        crtime                          1815247.75130736
        defer_xmts                      0
        duplex                          full
        ex_collisions                   0
        fcs_errors                      0
        first_collisions                0
        ierrors                         0
        ifspeed                         100000000
        intr                            1869597
        ipackets                        1488584
        ipackets64                      1488584
        macrcv_errors                   0
        macxmt_errors                   45
        media                           twpair
        missed                          0
        multi_collisions                0
        multircv                        0
        multixmt                        30405
        norcvbuf                        0
        noxmtbuf                        0
        obytes                          750185937
        obytes64                        5045153233
        oerrors                         45
        oflo                            0
        opackets                        5602789
        opackets64                      5602789
        promisc                         off
        rbytes                          162676612
        rbytes64                        162676612
        rcv_badinterp                   0
        runt_errors                     0
        snaptime                        2423664.10711802
        sqe_errors                      45
        toolong_errors                  0
        tx_late_collisions              0
        uflo                            0
        unknowns                        24
        xmt_badinterp                   0
        xmtretry                        921895

</screen>

<p>A full discussion of the meaning of the statistics is not given
here.  You should contact the author if you have specific questions
about any of these values.</p>

<section>Verifying Connectivity with the <tt>ping</tt>(1M) Command</section>

<p>The <tt>ping</tt>(1M) command can be used to verify connectivity
between two systems.  Typically this command is run with a single
option, which is the hostname or IP address to which you want to verify
connectivity.</p>

<p>This causes an ICMP (Internet Control Message Protocol) ECHO packet
to be sent to the specified host or IP address, which will normally
send a response packet back to the originating machine.
</p>

<note>Many sites restrict ICMP packets using firewalls.  In such a
case <tt>ping</tt> will not function correctly, even if normal
traffic would otherwise get through.  Ask your network administrator
for help if you believe this is the case at your site.
</note>

<p>The following demonstrates a test of connectivity to the
<tt>www.whitehouse.gov</tt> site:</p>

<screen>
% <entry>ping www.whitehouse.gov</entry>
www.whitehouse.gov is alive
</screen>

<p>
Note that unlike most of the other diagnostics presented in this
chapter, <tt>ping</tt> can be run without root privileges.
</p>

<chaphead>Appendix A - Software License</chaphead>
<a name="AppendixA"></a>

<p>
The software documented by this manual is covered under the following
terms:
</p>

<p>
Copyright &copy; 2001-2003 by Garrett D'Amore &lt;<a href="mailto:garrett@damore.org">garrett@damore.org</a>&gt;.
All rights reserved.
</p>
<p>
Redistribution and use in source and binary forms, with or without
modification, are permitted provided that the following conditions
are met:
</p>
<ol>
<li>Redistributions of source code must retain the above copyright
notice, this list of conditions and the following disclaimer.
</li>
<li>
Redistributions in binary form must reproduce the above copyright
notice, this list of conditions and the following disclaimer in the
documentation and/or other materials provided with the distribution.
</li>
<li>Neither the name of the author nor the names of any co-contributors
may be used to endorse or promote products derived from this software
without specific prior written permission.
</li>
</ol>

<p>
THIS SOFTWARE IS PROVIDED BY THE COPYRIGHT HOLDER AND CONTRIBUTORS ``AS IS''
AND ANY EXPRESS OR IMPLIED WARRANTIES, INCLUDING, BUT NOT LIMITED TO, THE
IMPLIED WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY AND FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE
ARE DISCLAIMED.  IN NO EVENT SHALL THE COPYRIGHT HOLDER OR CONTRIBUTORS BE
LIABLE FOR ANY DIRECT, INDIRECT, INCIDENTAL, SPECIAL, EXEMPLARY, OR
CONSEQUENTIAL DAMAGES (INCLUDING, BUT NOT LIMITED TO, PROCUREMENT OF
SUBSTITUTE GOODS OR SERVICES; LOSS OF USE, DATA, OR PROFITS; OR BUSINESS
INTERRUPTION) HOWEVER CAUSED AND ON ANY THEORY OF LIABILITY, WHETHER IN
CONTRACT, STRICT LIABILITY, OR TORT (INCLUDING NEGLIGENCE OR OTHERWISE)
ARISING IN ANY WAY OUT OF THE USE OF THIS SOFTWARE, EVEN IF ADVISED OF THE
POSSIBILITY OF SUCH DAMAGE.
</p>

<chaphead>Appendix B - Frequently Asked Questions</chaphead>

<ol>
<li><b>I installed the software, but I can't see my device.</b><br/>
This usually stems from failing to follow the documented procedures correctly.
The most common error is to attempt to configure or see the device with
<tt>ifconfig</tt>, without first "plumbing" it, as described in
<a href="#Chap3">Chapter 3</a>.  Also, make sure your device is on
the supported devices list.
<p/>
</li>

<li><b>Why won't my interface negotiate for full duplex?</b><br/>
A common misunderstanding is that all devices can operate in full-duplex
mode.  While most NICs, and most <strong>switches</strong> are capable
of full-duplex operation, <strong>hubs</strong> are generally not able
to operate in full-duplex mode.  If you are connecting to a hub, half-duplex
operation is normal.
<p/>
Also, make sure that if you are connecting to a switch, that you have
enabled autoconfiguration (sometimes called auto-sense) on the port.
<p/>
</li>

<li><b>Can I use this for diskless client or install Solaris (jumpstart) over it?</b><br/>
No.  On SPARC, network boot requires an FCode PROM, which is absent from most
or all NICs produced for the commodity PC market.  On x86 platforms, a real
mode driver is required, and one has not been written yet.  If you'd like
to volunteer to write a real mode driver, please contact the author.
<p/>
</li>

<li><b>Will this work with Solaris 7 or older on SPARC?</b><br/>
No, SPARC platforms require Solaris 8.  Changing this would be
non-trivial, since there is no GLD for Solaris 7 or older on SPARC.
<p/>
</li>

<li><b>Will this work with Solaris 2.6 or older on Intel?</b><br/>
No.  Changing this would be non-trivial, since there were substantial
changes to the GLD in Solaris 7.  (These changes give drivers based on
the GLDv2, such as these, much better performance.)
<p/>
</li>

<li><b>I really like this software.  How can I donate to the author?</b><br/>
The author greatly appreciates any donations which might help fund continued
development efforts.  A donation of $5 (five US dollars) per station using
these drivers is recommended, but any donation is gratefully accepted, and
none is obligatory.  The author has an account with 
<a href="http://www.paypal.com/">PayPal</a>, so you can donate
that way.  The easiest way to do this is to click the appropriate link
on the home page for these drivers at
<a href="http://garrett.damore.org/software/ethernet">http://garrett.damore.org/software/ethernet/</a>.
<p/>
</li>

</ol>

</body>
</html>
